Finding Aid for the Korean-American Oral History Project Collection LSC.1414
UCLA Library Special Collections
Korean-American Oral History Project collection
1975-1981
1975-1977
UCLA Library Special Collections
Korean-American Oral History Project
Sunoo, Sonia Shinn
University of California, Los Angeles. Asian American Studies Center
LSC.1414
6.0 Linear Feet (3 oversize boxes)
The Korean-American Oral History Project at the UCLA Asian American Studies Center was founded to develop oral history source materials on Korean American history during the 1903-45 period, and to facilitate their use by researchers. The tape-recorded oral histories of Korean American immigrants to the United States made by Sonia Shinn Sunoo form a part of that project. The collection consists of 31 cassette tape recordings of interviews with Korean immigrants to the United States.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains processed audiovisual materials. All requests to access materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of these materials are available for viewing in the Library Special Collections reading room.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Sonia Shinn Sunoo, 1985.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9919730203606533
Biography
The Korean-American Oral History Project at the UCLA Asian American Studies Center was founded to develop oral history source materials on Korean American history during the 1903-45 period, and to facilitate their use by researchers. Its goals are to collect individual memories of people and events, to develop an indexing project for the collection and to establish a permanent depository of these records at UCLA. The tape-recorded oral histories of Korean American immigrants to the United States made by Sonia Shinn Sunoo form a part of that project.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of 31 master cassette tape recordings of interviews with Korean immigrants to the United States and 31 duplicate copies. Boxes 1 and 2 of the collection contain the duplicate copies of the master cassettes contained in Box 3.
Audio cassettes.; Korean Americans -- California -- Interviews.; Korean-American Oral History Project--Archives.
- Master cassettes of interviews, 1975-1977, 1981 (Box 3)
  - 1A No. 9 Ahn, Joan, 1976 January 18; yrlsc_1414_003_001a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:25:24) (Box 3, Case 1)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are available for access. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  - 1B No. 3 Kim, Sung Jun, 1976 January 18; yrlsc_1414_003_001b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:30:12) (Box 3, Case 1)
  - 2A No 27 Sunoo, Kyong-Sin, 1975 November 25; yrlsc_1414_003_002a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:45:32) (Box 3, Case 2)
  - 2B No 44 Ahn, Seung-Wha, 1975 December 3; yrlsc_1414_003_002b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:45:32) (Box 3, Case 2)
  - 3A No 30 Ahn, Young-Ho, 1976 January 16; yrlsc_1414_003_003a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:31:58) (Box 3, Case 3)
  - 3B No 9 Ahn, Joan, 1976 January 16; yrlsc_1414_003_003b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:32:01) (Box 3, Case 3)
  - 4A No 90 Chang, Lee Wook, 1981 October 5; yrlsc_1414_003_004a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:46:38) (Box 3, Case 4)
  - 4B No 90 Chang, Lee Wook, 1981 October 5; yrlsc_1414_003_004b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:46:33) (Box 3, Case 4)
  - 5A No 90 Chang, Lee Wook, 1981 October 5; yrlsc_1414_003_005a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:45:00) (Box 3, Case 5)
  - 6A No. 65 Choi, N.Y., 1976 July 28; yrlsc_1414_003_006a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:28:37) (Box 3, Case 6)
  - 7A No 67 Chu, Young-Han, 1976 January 17; yrlsc_1414_003_007a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:30:23) (Box 3, Case 7)
  - 7B No 67 Chu, Young-Han, 1976 January 17; yrlsc_1414_003_007b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:28:12) (Box 3, Case 7)
  - 8A No. 39 Mr. Sang Ok Han & no.14 Mrs. Sang Ok Han, 1976 January 14; yrlsc_1414_003_008a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:27:46) (Box 3, Case 8)
  - 8B no.42 Yang Cho Eun, 1976 January 14; yrlsc_1414_003_008b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:31:52.000) (Box 3, Case 8)
  - 9A no.14 Mrs. Sang Ok Han pt 2 follow-up, 1977 February 2; yrlsc_1414_003_009a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:32:15) (Box 3, Case 9)
  - 9B no.14 Mrs. Sang Ok Han pt 2 follow-up, 1977 February 2; yrlsc_1414_003_009b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:33:43) (Box 3, Case 9)
  - 10A no.2 Kim Hei Won, 1975 December 18; yrlsc_1414_003_010a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:45:55) (Box 3, Case 10)
  - 10B no.2 Kim Hei Won, 1975 December 18; yrlsc_1414_003_010b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:39:44) (Box 3, Case 10)
  - 11A no.2 Kim Hei Won follow-up, 1977 February 23; yrlsc_1414_003_011a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:43:12) (Box 3, Case 11)
  - 11B no.2 Kim Hei Won follow-up, 1977 February 23; yrlsc_1414_003_011b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:44:04) (Box 3, Case 11)
  - 12A No. 48 Rev. Herbert Kim Hyung Sik, 1976 January 7; yrlsc_1414_003_012a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:30:01) (Box 3, Case 12)
  - 12B No. 48 Rev. Herbert Kim Hyung Sik, 1976 January 7; yrlsc_1414_003_012b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:29:55) (Box 3, Case 12)
  - 13A no.35 Kim Kyong Bo, 1975 December 5; yrlsc_1414_003_013a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:31:56) (Box 3, Case 13)
  - 13B no.35 Kim Hyong Soon, 1975 December 19; yrlsc_1414_003_013b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:09:04) (Box 3, Case 13)
  - 14A no.59 Rev. Sarah Kim, 1976 January 9; yrlsc_1414_003_014a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:31:03) (Box 3, Case 14)
  - 14B no.37 Kown Young Ho, 1976 January 9; yrlsc_1414_003_014b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:31:06) (Box 3, Case 14)
  - 15A no.57 Rev. Sung-Nak Kim, 1975 December 22; yrlsc_1414_003_015a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:30:09) (Box 3, Case 15)
  - 15B no.57 Rev. Sung-Nak Kim, 1975 December 22; yrlsc_1414_003_015b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:24:12) (Box 3, Case 15)
  - 16A no.49 Warren Kim, 1976 January 10; yrlsc_1414_003_016a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:30:50) (Box 3, Case 16)
  - 16B no.49 Warren Kim, 1976 January 10; yrlsc_1414_003_016b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:11:01) (Box 3, Case 16)
  - 17A no.49 Warren Kim, 1976 January 10; yrlsc_1414_003_017a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:30:29) (Box 3, Case 17)
  - 17B no.49 Warren Kim, 1976 January 10; yrlsc_1414_003_017b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:11:34) (Box 3, Case 17)
  - 18A no. Kim Young Chur, undated; yrlsc_1414_003_018a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:31:07) (Box 3, Case 18)
  - 18B no. Kim Young Chur, undated; yrlsc_1414_003_018b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:10:45) (Box 3, Case 18)
  - 19A no. Kim Young Chur, 1976 July 16; yrlsc_1414_003_019a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:31:53) (Box 3, Case 19)
  - 19B no. Kim Young Chur, undated; yrlsc_1414_003_019b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:31:56) (Box 3, Case 19)
  - 20A no.37 Kown Young Ho, 1976 January 9; yrlsc_1414_003_020a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:46:48) (Box 3, Case 20)
  - 20B no.49 Kim Warren, 1976 January 10; yrlsc_1414_003_020b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:46:49) (Box 3, Case 20)
  - 21A no.58 Lee Chang Hei, 1976 January 2; yrlsc_1414_003_021a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:31:43) (Box 3, Case 21)
  - 21B no.58 Lee Chang Hei, 1976 January 2; yrlsc_1414_003_021b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:31:23) (Box 3, Case 21)
  - 22A no.58 Mr. & Mrs. Chang Hei Lee, 1975 November 13; yrlsc_1414_003_022a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:30:55) (Box 3, Case 22)
  - 22B no.58 Mr. & Mrs. Chang Hei Lee, 1975 November 13; yrlsc_1414_003_022b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:30:56) (Box 3, Case 22)
  - 23A no.35 Lim Blanche, 1976 March 30; yrlsc_1414_003_023a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:07:10) (Box 3, Case 23)
  - 23B no.59 Kim Reverend Sara, 1976 January 9; yrlsc_1414_003_023b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:30:43) (Box 3, Case 23)
  - 24A no.35 Park Ne Gun, 1975 December 29; yrlsc_1414_003_024a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:30:08) (Box 3, Case 24)
  - 24B no.35 Park Ne Gun, 1975 December 29; yrlsc_1414_003_024b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:30:17) (Box 3, Case 24)
  - 25A no.35 Park Ne Gun, undated; yrlsc_1414_003_025a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:13:33) (Box 3, Case 25)
  - 26A no.41 Rhee Byong Uk, 1976 January 5; yrlsc_1414_003_026a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:30:07) (Box 3, Case 25)
  - 26B no.41 Rhee Byong Uk, 1976 January 5; yrlsc_1414_003_026b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:23:14) (Box 3, Case 26)
  - 27A no.4 Yang Choo Eun no.88 Helen Kim, undated; yrlsc_1414_003_027a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:29:53) (Box 3, Case 27)
  - 27B no.17 Mrs. Hyong Soon Kim, 1976 January 18; yrlsc_1414_003_027b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:17:40) (Box 3, Case 27)
  - 28A no.43 Mr. Do Yun Yoon & no.29 Mrs. Do Yun Yoon, 1975 November 28; yrlsc_1414_003_028a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:45:51) (Box 3, Case 28)
  - 28B no.43 Mr. Do Yun Yoon & no.29 Mrs. Do Yun Yoon, 1975 November 28; yrlsc_1414_003_028b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:23:27) (Box 3, Case 28)
  - 29A no.43 Mr. Do Yun Yoon & no.29 Mrs. Do Yun Yoon, 1975 November 28; yrlsc_1414_003_029a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:45:39) (Box 3, Case 29)
  - 29B no.43 Mr. Do Yun Yoon & no.29 Mrs. Do Yun Yoon, 1975 November 28; yrlsc_1414_003_029b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:23:23) (Box 3, Case 29)
  - 30A no.35 Leo Song, 1975 December 29; yrlsc_1414_003_030a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:30:53) (Box 3, Case 30)
  - 30B no.35 Leo Song, 1975 December 29; yrlsc_1414_003_030b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:30:59) (Box 3, Case 30)
  - 31A no.35 Leo Song, 1975 December 29; yrlsc_1414_003_031a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:29:19) (Box 3, Case 31)
  - 31B no.35 Leo Song, 1975 December 29; yrlsc_1414_003_031b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 00:29:44) (Box 3, Case 31)
- Copies of interviews, 1975-1977, 1981 (Box 1, Box 2)
  CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are available for access. All requests to access materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  Scope and Contents
  Contains copies of master interview audiocassettes.
  Existence and Location of Originals
  Original audiocassettes located in Box 3.